我不能放你出来的啊 海德薇
I can't let you out Hedwig
离开学校以后我就不能使用魔法
I'm not allowed to use magic outside of school
而且 如果被姨父他 哈利波特
Besides if Uncle Vernon Harry Potter
这下你高兴了吧
Now you've done it
他来了 威农
He's in there Vernon
我警告你
I'm warning you
如果你不管好那只笨鸟就得把它送走
if you can't control that bloody bird it'll have to go
它是因为无聊
But she's bored
只要我能把它放出去
If I could only let her out
一两个小时的话
for an hour or two
哈 好让你能送秘密讯息给你的怪胎朋友
So you can send secret messages to your freaky little friends
作梦
No sir
可是我一直都没有收到我朋友的任何讯息
But I haven't had any messages from any of my friends
一个都没有 整个夏天
Not one all summer
谁会跟你做朋友
Who would want to be friends with you
我想你该懂得感恩图报
I should think you'd be a little more grateful
我们从小把你养大
We've raised you since you were a baby
给你东西吃
given you the food off our table
甚至还把达力的小卧室也给你
even let you have Dudley's second bedroom
简直就是用尽一切心力对你好
purely out of the goodness of our hearts
还不可以 梅森先生来了才能吃
Not now It's for when the Masons arrive
他们随时都会到
Which should be any minute
现在呢 我们大家先来预习一下
Now let's go over our schedule once again shall we
佩妮 梅森夫妇到的时候你会在
Petunia when the Masons arrive you will be
在客厅里
In the lounge
准备用最亲切的态度欢迎他们光临
waiting to welcome them graciously to our home
好极了
Good
达力 你呢
And Dudley you will be
我会等着替他们开门
I'll be waiting to open the door
太好了
Excellent
那你呢
And you
我会在我的房间里
I'll be in my bedroom
不发出任何声音假装没有我这个人存在
making no noise and pretending that I don't exist
你知道就好
Too right you will
如果运气好的话
With any luck
我将会谈成这辈子最大的生意
this could be the day I make the biggest deal of my career
你绝对不准出来给我搞砸了
and you will not mess it up
哈利波特
Harry Potter
多么的荣幸啊
such an honor it is
你是谁
Who are you
多比
Dobby sir
家庭小精灵多比
Dobby the house elf
不是我不懂礼貌
Not to be rude or anything
可是现在我卧室里真的不适合招待家庭小精灵
but this isn't a great time for me to have a house elf in my bedroom
哦 没关系 多比完全了解
Yes sir Dobby understands
只是多比有件事情一定要说
It's just that Dobby has come to tell you
这 这实在是太难启齿了
It is difficult sir
多比不知道该怎么说
Dobby wonders where to begin
你要不要先坐下
Why don't you sit down
坐下
Sit down
坐 坐下
多比 对不起
Dobby I'm sorry
我不是故意要冒犯你的
I didn't mean to offend you or anything
冒犯多比
Offend Dobby
多比听说你是了不起的巫师
Dobby has heard of your greatness sir
但从来没有任何巫师问多比要不要坐下
but never has he been asked to sit down by a wizard
平等相待
like an equal
那你一定是没有碰到好巫师
You can't have met many decent wizards then
是 没有
No I haven't
我批评巫师是不对的
That was an awful thing to say
坏多比 坏多比 停下来 多比 多比 嘘
Bad Dobby Bad Dobby Stop Dobby Dobby shush
坏多比 多比 求求你
Bad Dobby Dobby please
停下来
stop
别管那个 那是猫
Don't mind that It's just the cat
坏多比 停下来
Bad Dobby Stop
停下来 多比 求求你
Stop Dobby Please be quiet
你还好吧
Are you all right
多比一定要惩罚他自己
Dobby had to punish himself sir
多比差点就说了他家庭的坏话
Dobby almost spoke ill of his family sir
家庭
Your family
就是多比服侍的那个巫师家庭
The wizard family Dobby serves sir
多比一辈子都得服侍同个家庭
Dobby is bound to serve one family forever
如果他们知道多比在你这里
If they ever knew Dobby was here
可是多比非来不可
But Dobby had to come
多比必须保护哈利波特
Dobby has to protect Harry Potter
得警告他
To warn him
哈利波特今年绝对不能回到霍格沃茨魔法巫师学校去
Harry Potter must not go back to Hogwarts School of Witchcraft and Wizardry this year
有一个阴谋
There is a plot
一个会发生很恐怖的事的阴谋
a plot to make most terrible things happen
什么恐怖的事情
What terrible things
谁在计划这个阴谋
Who's plotting them
我不能说
Can't say
好啦 我懂了 你不能说
Okay I understand You can't say
不要叫我说 我
Don't make me talk I
多比
Dobby
多比 把灯放下
Dobby put the lamp down
等他们打到第九洞以后
So when they arrive at the ninth hole
把灯给我
Give me the lamp
多比 放手
Dobby stop
给我进去 保持安静
Get in there and keep quiet
让我出去
Let me go
你在这里搞什么东西啊
What the devil are you doing up here
我只是
I was just
你打断了我日本人打高尔夫笑话中最好笑的地方了
You just ruined the punch line of my Japanese golfer joke
对不起
Sorry
你再出一点声音
One more sound
我保证让你死得很难看
and you'll wish you'd never been born boy
把那门修好
And fix that door
是
Yes sir
你现在知道我为什么想回去了
See why I've got to go back
我不属于这里
I don't belong here
我属于你们的世界
I belong in your world
霍格沃茨
at Hogwarts
我只有在那个地方才有朋友
It's the only place I've got friends
那些都不写信给哈利波特的朋友吗
Friends who don't write to Harry Potter
我想他们可能是
Well I expect they've been
等一下
Hang on
你怎么知道我的朋友没有写信给我
How do you know my friends haven't been writing to me
哈利波特千万不能生多比的气
Harry Potter mustn't be angry with Dobby
多比是想
Dobby hoped
如果哈利波特以为朋友都把他忘了
if Harry Potter thought his friends had forgotten him
哈利波特就不会再想回学校去
Harry Potter might not want to go back to school sir
把那些信给我
Give me those
现在
Now
不要
No
多比 快点回来
Dobby get back here
多比
Dobby
拜托 不要
please no
那哈利波特必须保证说
Harry Potter must say
他不会回学校去
he's not going back to school
我不能 霍格沃茨是我的家
I can't Hogwarts is my home
那多比非这样做不可了
Then Dobby must do it sir
这全是为了哈利波特好
for Harry Potter's own good
第一个水管工说这边流出了水
One plumber said "Look at all that water "
然后第二个水管工就说没错 这只是最上面的水
The second plumber said "Yes and that's just the top of it "
真的非常抱歉
I'm so sorry
我这个外甥 他脑袋有问题
It's my nephew He's very disturbed
看到陌生人就会发作
Meeting strangers upsets him
所以我才把他关在楼上
That's why I kept him upstairs
我不准你再回那个学校去
You're never going back to that school
我也不准你再去见你那些奇奇怪怪的朋友
You're never going to see those freaky friends of yours again
永远不准
Never
嗨 哈利
Hiya Harry
罗恩 佛瑞德 乔治
Ron Fred George
你们来干什么
What are you all doing here
当然是来救你的啦
Rescuing you of course
快去拿你的行李
Now come on get your trunk
你最好往后站一点
You better stand back
开始行动
Let's go
什么声音
What was that
波特
Potter
爸爸 发生什么事了
Dad what's going on
快点 哈利
Come on Harry
快啊
Hurry up
佩妮 这小子要逃跑了
Petunia he's escaping
哈利 快进来
I've got you Harry
你给我过来
Come here
放手
Let go of me
门都没有
No boy
你和那只死鸽子哪儿都别想去
You and that bloody pigeon aren't going anywhere
放开我
Get off
快开车
Drive
爸爸 你还好吧
Dad Are you okey
对了 哈利
By the way Harry
生日快乐
happy birthday
来吧
Come on
快点进来
Okay come on
快点
把这个拿走应该没关系吧
Think it'd be all right if we had some
没错 老妈不会知道的
Yeah Mum will never know
虽然不是很大
It's not much
但总是个家
but it's home
我觉得这里很棒
I think it's brilliant
你们几个家伙到底死到哪儿去了
Where have you been
哈利
Harry
能看到你真是太高兴了
how wonderful to see you dear
床上没人 没有留下任何纸条
Beds empty No note
偷开车子 你们有可能会死掉
Car gone You could have died
你们有可能被别人看到
You could have been seen
当然 我不是在说你 哈利
Of course I don't blame you Harry dear
他们让哈利饿肚子
They were starving him Mum
还把他的窗户封起来
There were bars on his window
你最好也祷告我不会把你的窗户给封起来
Well you best hope I don't put bars on your window
罗恩韦斯莱
Ronald Weasley
来吧 哈利 你该吃早餐了
Come on Harry time for a spot of breakfast
快吃 哈利 别客气
Here we are Harry Now tuck in
好极了 多吃一点
That's it There we go
妈妈 你有看到我的拖鞋吗
Mummy have you seen my jumper
亲爱的 就在猫的上面
Yes dear it was on the cat
你好
Hello
我 我哪里做错了
What did I do
是金妮 她整个夏天都在说你
Ginny She's been talking about you all summer
真是烦死人
A bit annoying really
早安 孩子们
Morning Weasleys
早安 爸爸
Morning Dad
昨天晚上真累
What a night
九次突袭检查
Nine raids
九次
Nine
检查
Raids
我爸他在魔法部上班
Dad works in the Ministry of Magic
他待在麻瓜人工制品滥用局
in the Misuse of Muggle Artifacts Office
他最爱麻瓜了
Dad loves Muggles
最迷麻瓜的东西
thinks they're fascinating
吃早餐了
Well now
你是谁
And who are you
对不起 先生
Sorry sir
我叫哈利 先生
I'm Harry sir
哈利波特
Harry Potter
我的天啊
Good Lord
你真的是
Are you really
恩 罗恩跟我们提过你的事
Well Ron has told us all about you
他什么时候来的
of course When did he get here
今天早上
This morning
你的儿子们半夜开着你那辆迷人的车子
Your sons flew that enchanted car of yours to
出去把他载来的
Surrey and back last night
真的吗
Did you really
车子性能还好吗 好的不得了
How did it go How useful really
我是说
I mean
你们这么做实在太不对了 孩子们
That was very wrong indeed boys
简直不可原谅
Very wrong of you
哈利 你一定很懂麻瓜
Now Harry you must know all about Muggles
告诉我
Tell me
那个橡皮鸭到底是做什么用的
what exactly is the function of a rubber duck
一定是爱洛送信来了
Well that'll be Errol with the post
派西 你去拿信 好吗
Fetch it will you Percy please
爱洛 爱洛每次都这样
Errol He's always doing that
是霍格沃茨寄来的信
Look it's our Hogwarts letters
他们也把哈利的信寄来了
They've sent us Harry's as well
邓不利多一定知道哈利也在这儿
Dumbledore must know you're here
他还真神通广大
Doesn't miss a trick that man
这些东西一点也不便宜
This lot won't come cheap
光是咒语书就非常贵
The spell books alone are very expensive
我们会想办法的
We'll manage
只有一个地方可以买到这些东西
There's only one place we're going to get all of this
斜角巷
Diagon Alley
好
Right
这个给你 哈利 你先去
Here we are Harry You go first dear
哈利从来没有用呼噜粉旅行过 妈妈
But Harry's never traveled by Floo powder before Mum
呼噜粉
Floo powder
那你先去吧让哈利看看这该怎么用
You go first Ron so that Harry can see how it's done Yes
你去吧
In you go That's it
斜角巷
Diagon Alley
看到了吗
You see
很简单 不要害怕
It's quite easy dear on't be afraid
来吧
Come on
来呀
快进去 小心你的头
In you go That's it Mind your head
就是这样 抓一把呼噜粉
That's right Now take your Floo powder
对了 就这么做
That's it very good
记住 一定要讲得非常的清楚
Now don't forget to speak very very clearly
血角巷
Diagonally
他刚才说什么
What did he say dear
血角巷
Diagonally
我想也是
I thought he did
你是不是迷路了 亲爱的
Not lost are you my dear
我没事 谢谢你
I'm fine thank you
我只是要去
I was just going
跟我们来吧
Come with us
我们会帮你找到回家的路
We'll help you find your way back
不用了 请 哈利
No Please Harry
海格
Hagrid
你怎么会来这种地方
What do you think you're doing down here
快过来
Come on
夜行巷
你脏死了 哈利
You're a mess Harry
偷偷在夜行巷晃来晃去
Skulking around Knockturn Alley
那里可不是好地方
Dodgy place
希望没人看你在那儿
Don't want no one to see you there
要不然大家会以为你做坏事
People will think you're up to no good
我是迷路了 我
I was lost I
等等 那你又去那里做什么
Hang on What were you doing down there then
我
Me
我是
I was
我去找一种肉食蛞蝓的杀虫剂
I was looking for Flesh Eating Slug Repellent
它们快把学校的包心菜吃光了
They're ruining all the school cabbages
哈利
Harry
海格
Hagrid
你好 赫敏
Hello Hermione
看到你真是太高兴了
It's so good to see you
我也很高兴看到你
It's great to see you too
你的眼镜怎么了
What did you do to your glasses
眼镜 回复
Oculus Reparo
我得把这个咒语记下来才行
I definitely need to remember that one
看来你应该安全了 哈利
You'll be all right now then Harry
好
Right
我就把你留在这儿了
I'll leave you to it
好 再见 谢了 再见
Okay bye Thank you Bye
快点 大家都好担心
Come on everyone's been so worried
神奇的我
喔 哈利
Oh Harry
感谢老天爷 我们一直希望你只是出了比较远的炉栅
Thank goodness We'd hoped you'd only gone one grate too far
各位
Ladies and gentlemen
我们欢迎吉尔德罗伊洛克哈特先生
Mr Gilderoy Lockhart
他来了
Here he is
妈妈最迷他了
Mum fancies him
麻烦请让一让
Make way there please
太太 借过一下 谢谢
Let me by madam Thank you
不好意思 小朋友
Excuse me little girl
这是为预言家日报拍的
This is for the Daily Prophet
这该不会是哈利波特吧
It can't be Harry Potter
哈利波特
Harry Potter
不好意思 夫人
Excuse me madam
笑容大一点 哈利 我们的合照将会登上头版
Nice big smile Harry Together you and I rate the front page
各位女士 各位先生 这真是不平凡的一刻
Ladies and gentlemen what an extraordinary moment this is
哈利波特今天早上特地踏进了华丽与污痕书店
When young Harry stepped into Flourish and Blotts this morning
来购买我的自传
to purchase my autobiography Magical Me
顺便提一下这本书最近
which incidentally is currently
刚好登上预言家日报畅销书排行榜的第27周榜首
celebrating its 27th week atop the Daily Prophet bestseller list
哈利绝对不会想到
he had no idea
他也不会相信
that he would in fact believing
他将会得到我的全套著作
with my entire collected works
完全免费
free of charge
现在 女士们
Now ladies
哈利 我帮你拿
Harry now you give me those
我要拿给他签名
and I'll get them signed
你们都到外头去等我吧
All of you wait outside
快
That's it
我想你一定很过瘾吧 波特
I'll bet you loved that didn't you Potter
出名的哈利波特
Famous Harry Potter
连到书店都会登上报纸头版
Can't even go into a bookshop without making the front page
你少来烦他
Leave him alone
得了 波特
Look Potter
你交新女朋友了
You've got yourself a girlfriend
别这样 德拉科
Now now Draco
亲切一点
play nicely
波特先生
Mr Potter
我是鲁休思马尔福
Lucius Malfoy
我们终于见面了
We meet at last
等一下
Forgive me
你的疤痕可是种传奇
Your scar is legend
这可是某个巫师留给你的
As of course is the wizard who gave it to you
佛地魔杀了我的父母
Voldemort killed my parents
他不过是个杀人犯没什么了不起
He was nothing more than a murderer
你敢直呼他的名字不是特别大胆
You must be very brave to mention his name
就是特别蠢
Or very foolish
不敢直呼对方的名字
Fear of a name
只会更加深你的恐惧
only increases fear of the thing itself
你应该是
And you must be
格兰杰小姐
Miss Granger
没错 德拉科跟我提过你的事
Yes Draco has told me all about you
还有你的父母
And your parents
他们都是麻瓜
Muggles
不是吗
aren't they
我想想
Let me see
红头发
Red hair
一脸痴呆
vacant expressions
还有 破旧的二手书
tatty secondhand book
你们应该就是韦斯莱一家了
You must be the Weasleys
孩子们 这里有点乱 我们出去吧
It's mad in here Let's go outside
哎哎哎 韦斯莱
Well well well Weasley senior
鲁休思
Lucius
在魔法部一定很忙吧 亚瑟
Busy time at the Ministry Arthur
那么多突击检查
all those extra raids
希望他们有付你加班费
I do hope they're paying you overtime
但照你们目前的样子来看
but judging by the state of this
他们应该是没有
I'd say not
要是魔法部连像样的薪水都付不出来的话
What's the use in being a disgrace to the name of wizard
你又何苦侮辱巫师名声呢
if they don't even pay you well for it
我认为我们在侮辱巫师名声这件事上有不同的看法
We have a very different idea about what disgraces the name of wizard
马尔福
Malfoy
的确
Clearly
跟那些麻瓜往来
Associating with Muggles
我看你家真是堕落到了极点
And I thought your family could sink no lower
我们上班见了
I'll see you at work
我们学校见了
See you at school
10点58分了 快点
10:58 Come on
快点 列车快开了
The train will be leaving any moment
弥雷 乔治 派西 你们先
Fred George Percy you first
然后是你 亲爱的
After you dear
快点 金妮 快去找座位 快
Come on Ginny we'll get you a seat Hurry
该我们了
Let's go
你们俩在干什么
What do you two think you're doing
抱歉
Sorry
我们有点控制不住推车
Lost control of the trolley
为什么我们过不去
Why can't we get through
我不知道 我不知道入口为什么被封起来
I don't know The gateway has sealed itself for some reason
列车在11点就会准时开走
The train leaves at exactly 11 :00
我们错过列车了
We've missed it
哈利
Harry
如果我们过不去
if we can't get through
爸跟妈可能也出不来
maybe Mum and Dad can't get back
也许我们应该
Maybe we should
回到车子旁边去等
just go and wait by the car
车子
The car
罗恩 我必须告诉你
Ron I should tell you
大部份的麻瓜都没有看过会飞的车子
most Muggles aren't accustomed to seeing a flying car
对喔
Right
喔 不
Oh no
一定是隐形发射器故障了
The lnvisibility Booster must be faulty
那么这样 我们飞低一点
Come on then Let's go lower
我们要赶快找到列车
We need to find the train
好
Okay
我们只要追上列车就可以了
All we need to do is catch up with the train
应该不会太远
We can't be far behind
你听到了吗
Do you hear that
我们快要赶上了
We must be getting close
等等
Hold on
哈利
Harry
抓紧点
Hold on
抓住我的手
Take my hand
撑着点
Hold on
我正在努力
I'm trying
你的手心都是汗水
Your hand's all sweaty
我们找到列车了
I think we found the train
是啊
Yeah
欢迎回家
Welcome home
往上 往上
Up Up
坏掉了
It's not working
往上 罗恩 小心那棵树
Up Ron mind that tree
快停 停 停
Stop Stop Stop
我的魔杖
My wand
你看我的魔杖
Look at my wand
你该庆幸那不是你的脖子
Be thankful it's not your neck
怎么了 我也不知道
What's happening I don't know
赶快发动车子
Come on go
快
Fast
斑斑 你没事吧
Scabbers you're okay
车子
The car
爸爸一定会宰了我
Dad's gonna kill me
待会见 海德薇
See you Hedwig
我的房里出现了个家庭小精灵
So a house elf shows up in my bedroom
然后我们无法进入九又四分之三月台
we can't get through the barrier to platform 9 3/4
然后又差点被一棵树给打死
we almost get killed by a tree
很明显地有人不想我回到学校
Clearly someone doesn't want me here this year
喔 看看你们两个
Well take a good look lads
这可能是
This night might well be
你们最后一次待在这里了
the last you spend in this castle
你们的麻烦大了
Oh dear we are in trouble
至少有七个麻瓜看到你们
You were seen by no less than seven Muggles
你们可知道这件事有多严重
Do you have any idea how serious this is
你们差一点就让我们的世界被公诸于世
You have risked the exposure of our world
更别说你们还造成浑拼柳严重的损害
Not to mention the damage you inflicted on a Whomping Willow
这棵树可比你们的年纪还要大
that's been on these grounds since before you were born
老实说 斯内普教授
Honestly Professor Snape
浑拼柳对我们的伤害更大
I think it did more damage to us
住口
Silence
我向你们保证
I assure you
如果你们是史莱哲林的学生
that were you in Slytherin
而我有权力决定你们的命运时
and your fate rested with me
你们两个
the both of you
保证今晚就得搭列车回家
would be on the train home tonight
而且 他们不用回家
As it is They are not
邓不利多教授
Professor Dumbledore
麦格教授
Professor McGonagall
校长
Headmaster
这两个孩子他们的所做所为藐视了
these boys have flouted
未成年巫师限制法令基于我是本校
the Decree for the Restriction of Underage Wizardry As such
我非常明白
I am well aware of
所有的法规 其中很多条款都是我制定的
our bylaws Severus having written quite a few of them myself
可是
However
基于麦格教授才是格兰芬多的学院领导人
as head of Gryffindor house it is for Professor McGonagall
因此她才有权决定如何处罚
to determine the appropriate action
我们马上去收拾行李
We'll go and get our stuff then
你在说什么 韦斯莱
What are you talking about Mr Weasley
你不是要开除我们吗
You're going to expel us aren't you
不是今天 韦斯莱先生
Not today Mr Weasley
可是我必须让你们两个人记住
but I must impress on both of you
你们犯下了多么严重的错误
the seriousness of what you have done
今天晚上我就写信通知你们的家人
I will be writing to your families tonight
还要罚你们两个劳动服务
and you will both receive detention
早上好 同学们
Morning everyone
同学们 早上好 苗芽教授 早上好
Good morning everyone Good morning Professor Sprout
欢迎各位二年级同学来到三号温室
Welcome to Greenhouse Three second years
现在大家靠过来
Gather around everyone
我们今天要替曼德拉草换盆
Today we're going to re pot Mandrakes
有谁可以告诉我曼德拉草的根有什么用途
Who here can tell me the properties of the Mandrake root
好 格兰杰小姐
Yes Miss Granger
曼德拉草 又名曼陀罗草
Mandrake or Mandragora
通常是用来帮助被石化的人
is used to return those who have been Petrified
使他们能够恢复原形
to their original state
它也具有相当的危险性
It's also quite dangerous
听到曼德拉草的哭声有可能使人致命
The Mandrake's cry is fatal to anyone who hears it
太好了 格兰芬多加十分
Excellent Ten points to Gryffindor
我们的曼德拉草现还只是小幼苗
As our Mandrakes are still only seedlings
它们的哭声还不足以致命
their cries won't kill you yet
但还足以把你们昏迷几个小时
But they could knock you out for several hours
所以我才给你们这些耳罩以便挡住声音
which is why I have given you earmuffs for auditory protection
现在请大家马上戴上耳罩
So could you please put them on right away
请快点
Quickly
紧紧的盖住
Flaps tight down
大家仔细的看着我
and watch me closely
先紧紧的抓住曼德拉草
You grasp your Mandrake firmly
然后用力的把它从土里拉出来
You pull it sharply up out of the pot
然后再
Got it And
把它埋到另外一个盆子里
now you dunk it down into the other pot
然后再洒上一撮土壤
and pour a little sprinkling of soil
让它保持温暖这样就行了
to keep him warm
隆巴顿同学忘了他的耳罩了
Longbottom's been neglecting his earmuffs
不是 教授 他只是昏倒了
No ma'am he's just fainted
没错
Yes well
别管他了
just leave him there
好了 现在
Right on we go
我们要帮曼德拉草换盆
Plenty of pots to go around
抓住你们的曼德拉草
Grasp your Mandrake
用力拉出来
and pull it up
那是差点没头的尼克
There's Nearly Headless Nick
你好 派西
Hello Percy
清水小姐
Miss Clearwater
你好 尼克爵士
Hello Sir Nicholas
你说吧
Say it
我完了
I'm doomed
你不会的
You don't
嗨 哈利
Hi Harry
我是柯林克利维
I'm Colin Creevey
我也在格兰芬多
I'm in Gryffindor too
嗨 柯林 很高兴认识你
Hi Colin Nice to meet you
罗恩 那是你的猫头鹰吗
Ron is that your owl
这只鸟真是太可怕了
Bloody bird's a menace
喔 不
Oh no
大家快看
Look everyone
罗恩收到一封咆哮信耶
Weasley's got himself a Howler
快看吧 罗恩
Go on Ron
我有次不理我奶奶的咆哮信
I ignored one from my gran once
后果好可怕
It was horrible
罗恩韦斯莱
Ronald Weasley
你竟敢偷偷的开走那辆车
How dare you steal that car
你的行为真是可耻
I am absolutely disgusted
你父亲现在得接受工作单位的调查
Your father's now facing an inquiry at work
这全都是你的错
and it's entirely your fault
你要是敢再犯任何的错误
If you put another toe out of line
我们马上去带你回来
we 'll bring you straight home
喔 亲爱的金妮
And Ginny dear
恭喜你进了格兰芬多
congratulations on making Gryffindor
你爸爸跟我都以你为傲
Your father and I are so proud
现在让我为大家介绍
Let me introduce you
你们黑魔法防御课的新教授
to your new Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher
那就是我
Me
吉尔德罗伊洛克哈特
Gilderoy Lockhart
梅林勋章的第三级巫师
Order of Merlin Third Class
黑魔法防御术联盟最崇高的荣誉会员
honorary member of the Dark Force Defense League
同时也是女巫周刊迷人笑容奖五次冠军得主
and five times winner of Witch Weekly's Most Charming Smile Award
但是我不想提这些事情
But I don't talk about that
我可不是靠着我的迷人笑容来除妖的
I didn't get rid of the Bandon Banshee by smiling at him
现在
Now
请注意
be warned
我的职责呢 就是教大家如何
It is my job to arm you
对付魔法世界最恶心的怪物
against the foulest creatures known to wizardkind
你们马上就会在教室中面对最深的恐惧
You may find yourselves facing your worst fears in this room
但是只要有我在这里你们就会安然无恙
Know only that no harm can befall you whilst I am here
请大家千万不要尖叫
I must ask you not to scream
这样会激怒他们的
It might provoke them
康沃尔小精灵
Cornish pixies
刚被逮到的康沃尔小妖精
Freshly caught Cornish pixies
尽量的笑吧 西莫同学
Laugh if you will Mr Finnegan
这些小妖精可是非常难缠的小恶魔
but pixies can be devilishly tricky little blighters
来看看你们该怎么办
Let's see what you make of them
飞吧 飞
Come on now
大家快点动手 快点他们不过是绿仙
round them up They're only pixies
拜托 快放我下来
Please get me down
放开我 别动
Get off me Stop
不要动
Hold still
皮斯克皮克斯 皮斯特诺米
Peskipiksi Pesternomi
我给你们机会把剩下绿仙抓回笼子里面
I'll ask you three to just nip the rest of them back into their cage
我们现在该怎么办
What do we do now
全部定身
Immobulus
为什么每次都是我
Why is it always me
我整个暑假都在设计
I spent the summer devising
全新的魁地奇训练计划
a whole new Quidditch program
我们的训练必须更早
We're gonna train earlier
更严
harder
更久
and longer
搞什么东西
What I don't believe it
你们要去哪里 福林
Where you think you're going Flint
魁地奇球场
Quidditch practice
我已经登记包下今天的球场了
I booked the pitch for Gryffindor today
别激动 我得到许可
Easy Wood I've got a note
好像有麻烦了
I smell trouble
我 斯内普教授
I Professor Severus Snape
特别允许史莱哲林球队
do hereby give the Slytherin team
在今日使用魁地奇球场
permission to practice today
让他们训练新的搜捕手
owing to the need to train their new Seeker
你们有新搜捕手啊
You've got a new Seeker
谁啊
Who
马尔福
Malfoy
没错
That's right
我不算是最新的一份子
And that's not all that's new this year
那是光轮两干零一号
Those are Nimbus 2001 s
你们怎么会有这个
How did you get those
是马尔福的父亲送的
A gift from Malfoy's father
韦斯莱 这对我父亲来说只是花点小钱而已
You see Weasley unlike some my father can afford the best
至少 格兰芬多的队员都是凭真本事
At least no one on the Gryffindor team had to buy their way in
他们不是靠钱才入选的
They got in on pure talent
没有人问你的意见
No one asked your opinion
你这肮脏的小泥巴种
you filthy little Mudblood
你要为你说的话付出代价 马尔福
You'll pay for that one Malfoy
吃蛞蝓吧
Eat slugs
你还好吧 罗恩
You okay Ron
说说话
Say something
哇 可不可以把他转过来 哈利
Wow Can you turn him around Harry
不行 柯林 快让开
No Colin get out of the way
我们带他去找海格
Let's take him to Hagrid's
他一定知道该怎么办
He'll know what to do
这得用特别的设备才行
This calls for a specialist's equipment
恐怕只能等他自己停止吐了
Nothing to do but wait till it stops I'm afraid
好啦
Okay
出来总比进去好
Better out than in
罗恩到底要对谁下咒
Who was Ron trying to curse anyway
是马尔福
Malfoy
他叫赫敏
He called Hermione
我也不懂那是什么意思
Well I don't know exactly what it means
他叫我泥巴种
He called me a Mudblood
不会吧
He did not
泥巴种是什么意思
What's a Mudblood
意思是肮脏的血统
It means dirty blood
那是对出自麻瓜家庭的人最不敬的称呼
Mudblood's a really foul name for someone who's Muggle born
也就是父母不懂魔法
Someone with non magic parents
像我这样的人
Someone like me
这种话在有教养的对话总是听不到的
It's not a term one usually hears in civilized conversation
你知道了吧 哈利
See the thing is Harry
有些巫师
there are some wizards
就像马尔福他们一样
like the Malfoy family
自认为自己是血统纯正而充满了优越感
who think they're better than everyone else because they're pure blood
真是可恶
That's horrible
真是恶心
It's disgusting
那简直是一派胡言
And it's codswallop to boot
肮脏血统
Dirty blood
现在世上的巫师
Why there isn't a wizard alive today
多多少少都有一点混血
that's not half blood or less
更何况 还没有哪个巫师
More to the point they've yet to
能发明出赫敏学不会的魔咒
think of a spell that our Hermione can't do
过来
Come here
你不这么想吗 赫敏
Don't you think on it Hermione
你从来没有这样想过吗
Don't you think on it for one minute
哈利 哈利 哈利
Harry Harry Harry
你自己想一想
Can you possibly imagine
有比帮我回信还要更好的劳动服务方式了吗
a better way to serve detention than by helping me to answer my fan mail
是没有
Not really
名气是不可靠的朋友 哈利
Fame is a fickle friend Harry
名人来自于名人的作为
Celebrity is as celebrity does
千万别忘了
Remember that
来啊
Come
到我这来
to me
Come to me
什么
What
Sorry
那个声音
That voice
声音
Voice
你没有听到吗
Didn't you hear it
你在说什么 哈利
What are you talking about Harry
我想你大概是有一点
I think you're getting a bit
困了吧
drowsy
怪不得 看看现在几点了
And great Scott no wonder Look at the time
已经过了四个钟头了
We've been here nearly four hours
欢乐的时光总是过得特别的快
Spooky how the time flies when one is having fun
好怪
Spooky
血
Blood
我闻到鲜血
I smell blood
我要撕裂你
Let me rip you
我要杀了你
Let me kill you
杀了你
Kill
哈利
Harry
你有没有听到
Did you hear it
听到什么
Hear what
那个声音
That voice
声音 什么声音
Voice What voice
我刚刚在洛克哈特的办公室听到
I heard it first in Lockhart' s office
然后刚刚又
And then again just
杀戮
Kill
杀戮时间到了
It's time
声音在移动
It's moving
我想他要去杀人了
I think it's going to kill
杀人
Kill
哈利 等等 别跑那么快
Harry wait Not so fast
好奇怪
Strange
我从来没有看过蜘蛛这样跑的
I've never seen spiders act like that
我最讨厌蜘蛛了
I don't like spiders
那是什么
What's that
密室已经打开
The Chamber of Secrets has been opened
继承人的仇敌们 当心了
Enemies of the Heir beware
是用血写的
It's written in blood
喔 天啊
Oh no
那是飞七的猫
It's Filch's cat
诺里斯太太
It's Mrs Norris
继承人的仇敌 当心了
Enemies of the Heir beware
你就是下一个 麻种
You'll be next Mudbloods
你们在这里做什么
What's going on here
快点 让开 让开
Go on Make way make way
波特
Potter
你在
What are you
诺里斯太太
Mrs Norris
你竟然杀了我的猫
You've murdered my cat
没有 没有
No No
我要杀了你
I'll kill you
飞七
Argus
不要冲动
How loose sad
所有的人
Everyone
马上回到自己的宿舍去不准出来
will proceed to their dormitories immediately
除了 你们三个
Everyone except you three
雷文克劳同学跟我来
Ravenclaws follow me
她没有死 飞七
She's not dead Argus
她只是被石化了
She has been Petrified
我就知道
Thought so
真可惜我不在现场
So unlucky I wasn't there
我刚好知道拯救她的解咒术
I know exactly the countercurse that could've spared her
可是我不知道她是怎么被石化的
But how she has been Petrified I cannot say
问他
Ask him
都是他干的好事
It's him that's done it
你看到他在墙上写的字了
You saw what he wrote on the wall
不是我 校长 我发誓
It's not true sir I swear
我根本没碰过诺里斯太太
I never touched Mrs Norris
胡说八道
Rubbish
依我看 校长
If I might headmaster
或许波特和他的朋友们
Perhaps Potter and his friends
只是刚好在这里出现
were simply in the wrong place at the wrong time
不过
However
我觉得这整件事情实在太可疑
the circumstances are suspicious
我不记得晚上大家用餐时候有看过波特
I for one don't recall seeing Potter at dinner
他在我那里 斯内普
I'm afraid that's my doing Severus
哈利他在帮我回信给书迷
You see Harry was helping me answer my fan mail
所以我跟罗恩才会去找哈利
That's why Ron and l went looking for him professor
我们碰到他的时候 他说
We'd just found him when he said
说 说了什么
Yes Miss Granger
我告诉他们我很饿
When I said I wasn't hungry
就在我们一起回交谊厅的时候看到了诺里斯太太
We were heading back to the common room when we found Mrs Norris
在证明有罪之前 他是无辜的
Innocent until proven guilty Severus
我的猫被石化了
My cat has been Petrified
我要见到有人被惩罚
I want to see some punishment
我们会治好她的 飞七
We will be able to cure her Argus
据我的了解
As I understand it
芽菜夫人
Madam Sprout
培育出了非常健康的曼德拉草
has a very healthy growth of Mandrake
等它们成熟后制造出解药
When matured a potion will be made
就可以让诺里斯太太复原了
which will revive Mrs Norris
在这段期间
And in the meantime
我建议大家最好都谨慎行事
I strongly recommend caution
千万记住
to all
这真的很奇怪 对不对
It's a bit strange isn't it
奇怪
Strange
你听到了这个声音
You hear this voice
只有你才能听得到
a voice only you can hear
然后诺里斯太太就被石化了
and then Mrs Norris turns up Petrified
这真的很奇怪
It's just strange
你想我要不要告诉他们
Do you think I should have told them
告诉邓不利多和其他的人
Dumbledore and the others I mean
你疯啦
Are you mad
不行 哈利
No Harry
即使在巫师的世界
Even in the wizarding world
听见怪声音也不是好现象
hearing voices isn't a good sign
他说得很有道理
She's right you know
各位同学请听我说
Could I have your attention please
很好
Right
今天呢
Now today
我们要把动物
we will be transforming animals
变成高脚杯
into water goblets
就像这样
Like so
一 二 三
One two three
沸啦唯杜
Vera Verto
现在换你们了
Now it's your turn
谁要先来示范呢
Who would like to go first
韦斯莱同学
Mr Weasley
一 二 三
One two three
沸啦唯杜
Vera Verto
沸啦瓦杜
你该换一把魔杖了 韦斯莱先生
That wand needs replacing Mr Weasley
什么事 格兰杰
Yes Miss Granger
教授
Professor
不知道你能不能告诉我们
I was wondering if you could tell us
关于密室的事情
about the Chamber of Secrets
好吧
Very well
我想大家都知道
You all know of course
霍格沃茨是在一千多年前
that Hogwarts was founded over a thousand years ago
由当时最伟大的四位巫师和女巫所创办的
by the four greatest witches and wizards of the age
高瑞克格兰芬多
Godric Gryffindor
海加赫奇帕奇
Helga Hufflepuff
罗威娜拉文克劳
Rowena Ravenclaw
以及萨拉札斯莱特林
and Salazar Slytherin
其中的三位创办者呢他们相处的十分融洽
Now three of the founders coexisted quite harmoniously
有一位则不是
One did not
想也知道是谁
Three guesses who
萨拉札斯莱特林
Salazar Slytherin
希望能够进一步的筛选过
wished to be more selective
被获准入学的学生
about the students admitted to Hogwarts
他相信
He believed
只有魔法家庭的子弟才能学习魔法
magical learning should be kept within all magic families
也就是说要血统纯正
In other words pure bloods
他因为无法说服其他人
Unable to sway the others
因此离开了这所学校
he decided to leave the school
而根据传说呢
Now according to legend
斯莱特林在城堡中建了一个隐藏的房间
Slytherin had built a hidden chamber in this castle
大家都把这个房间称为密室
known as the Chamber of Secrets
就在他离开学校之前
Though shortly before departing
他封住了密室
he sealed it
直到他真正的传人回到了学校
until that time when his own true Heir returned to the school
这个传人
The Heir alone
将会打开那个密室
would be able to open the Chamber
释放出里面恐怖的东西
and unleash the horror within
到那个时候
and by so doing
便能除掉学校中所有的
purge the school of all those who
斯莱特林认为
in Slytherin's view
没有资格学习魔法的人
were unworthy to study magic
麻瓜的后代
Muggle borns
当然学校人员进行过好几次的搜寻
Naturally the school has been searched many times
但是并没有找到这样的密室
No such chamber has been found
麦格教授
Professor
传说有没有告诉我们
What exactly does legend tell us
密室中的东西是什么
lies within the Chamber
传说密室中的那个东西唯有斯莱特林的后人才能掌控
The Chamber is said to be home to something that only the Heir of Slytherin can control
听说里面住了一个
It is said to be the home
可怕的怪兽
of a monster
这会是真的吗
Do you think it's true
你们想真的有所谓的密室吗
Do you think there really is a Chamber of Secrets
当然有
Yes
你看不出来吗
Couldn't you tell
麦格教授很担心
McGonagall's worried
所有的教授也是
All the teachers are
但是如果有所谓的密室
If there really is a Chamber of Secrets
真的被打开了那就表示
and it really has been opened that means
斯莱特林的传人已经回到了学校
The Heir of Slytherin has returned to Hogwarts
问题在于
The question is
他是谁
who is it
大家想想看
Let's think
我们认识的人里
Who do we know who thinks
有谁把麻瓜后代看成人渣
all Muggle borns are scum
如果你是说马尔福的话
If you're talking about Malfoy
当然 你也听到他的话了
Of course You heard him
你就是下一个麻种
You'll be next Mudbloods
我听到了
I heard him
可是马尔福 斯莱特林的传人
But Malfoy the Heir of Slytherin
或许罗恩说得没错 赫敏
Maybe Ron's right Hermione
你看他的家人
I mean look at his family
他们家人几百年来都是斯莱特林的学生
The whole lot of them have been in Slytherin for centuries
克拉克跟高尔一定知道
Crabbe and Goyle must know
或许我们可以向他们套一些话
Maybe we could trick them into telling
他们还没笨到那种程度
Even they aren't that thick
或许还有别的方法
But there might be another way
我提醒你们 这方法很困难
Mind you it would be difficult
我们至少得违反五十条校规
Not to mention we'd be breaking about 50 school rules
而且这方法很危险
and it'll be dangerous
十分的危险
Very dangerous
超强魔药
找到了
Here it is
所谓的变身水
The Polyjuice Potion
只要作出正确的调配
Properly brewed
这种魔药就可以让喝下的人暂时的完全变成
the Polyjuice Potion allows the drinker to transform himself temporarily into
另外一个人的样子
the physical form of another
你是说哈利跟我喝下那个东西
You mean if Harry and I drink that stuff
就会变成克拉克与高尔
we'll turn into Crabbe and Goyle
对
Yeah
太帅了
Wicked
马尔福肯定会说出一切
Malfoy will tell us anything
没有错
Exactly
这药很难做 我从来没见过这么复杂的配方
But it's tricky I've never seen a more complicated potion
那要多久才能配好
How long will it take to make
一个月
A month
可是 赫敏
But Hermione
如果马尔福是斯莱特林的传人
if Malfoy is the Heir of Slytherin
在一个月以内 他至少可以攻击一半以上的麻瓜后代
he could attack half the Muggle borns in the school by then
我知道
I know
但我们只有这个方法
But it's the only plan we've got
斯莱特林再得分
Another goal for Slytherin
以90比30领先格兰芬多
They lead Gryffindor 90 to 30
注意了 大疤头
All right there Scarhead
小心点 哈利
Watch yourself Harry
伍德 小心
Wood look out
啊呀 脾气暴躁的搏格盯住哈利
Blimey Harry's got himself a rogue Bludger
简直是太过分了
That's been tampered with that has
我要阻止它
I'll stop it
不 就算你的魔杖没坏掉都很危险了
No Even with a proper wand it's too risky
你可能会击中哈利
You could hit Harry
你在跳芭雷舞 波特
Training for the ballet Potter
你追不上我的 波特
You'll never catch me Potter
快过去
Let's go
哈利波特捕到了金探子
Harry Potter has caught the Snitch
格兰芬多获胜
Gryffindor wins
非腻特 因砍塔腾
Finite Incantatem
谢谢 你还吧
Thank you Are you okay
不好 我想我的手臂断掉了
No I think my arm is broken
别担心 哈利我马上就可以帮你把手臂医好
Not to worry Harry I will fix that arm of yours straightaway
不 你不必了
No Not you
喔 可怜 已经语无伦次了
Boy doesn't know what he's saying
放心 一点都不会痛
This won't hurt a bit
手臂恢复
Brackium Emendo
没错 呃
Yes well
有的时候会是这样没错
that can sometimes happen
不过呢
but
重点是
the point is
你再也不会痛了
you can no longer feel any pain
而且你的手臂再也不会骨折了
and very clearly the bones are not broken
骨折
Broken
他连骨头都没了
There's no bones left
可是弹性蛮好的
Much more flexible though
好了 马尔福 别再叫了你可以出院了
Mr Malfoy stop making such a fuss You can go
让开
Out of my way
你们要是直接送来
Should have been brought straight to me
我就能修好骨头
I can mend bones in a heartbeat
现在要让骨头长回来就
but growing them back
你能治好他吧
You will be able to won't you
我当然可以治好他
I'll be able to certainly
会有点疼就是了
But it'll be painful
今天晚上会不太好受 波特
You're in for a rough night Potter
重新长骨头是件不舒服的事
Regrowing bones is a nasty business
你还希望是什么 南瓜汁
What do you expect Pumpkin juice
杀戮
Kill
你好
Hello
多比
Dobby
哈利波特应该听多比的话
Harry Potter should have listened to Dobby
哈利波特赶不上火车的时候就该回家了
Harry Potter should have gone back home when he missed the train
是你
It was you
是你封住站台
You stopped the barrier
让我跟罗恩没办法过去
from letting Ron and me through
老实说
Indeed
没错
Yes sir
你差点害我跟罗恩被开除
You nearly got Ron and me expelled
至少这样能让你离开这里
At least you would be away from here
哈利波特必须回家
Harry Potter must go home
多比以为他的博格
Dobby thought his Bludger
可以让哈利波特明白
would beenough to make Harry Potter see
你的博格
Your Bludger
是你让游走球拼命追我的
You made that Bludger chase after me
多比真的觉得很难过
Dobby feels most aggrieved sir
多比还用熨斗烫他自己的手
Dobby had to iron his hands
你最好在我骨头长出前说清楚否则我一定会掐死你
You better clear off before my bones come back Dobby or I might strangle you
多比已经习惯这样的威胁了
Dobby is used to death threats sir
多比在家里一天至少要被威胁五次
Dobby gets them five times a day at home
我想你是不打算告诉我你为什么要杀我
I don't suppose you could tell me why you're trying to kill me
我不是要杀你
Not kill you sir
我不会杀你的
Never kill you
多比还记得哈利波特打败
Dobby remembers how it was before Harry Potter triumphed
不能说出名字的那个人前我们过着什么样的生活
over He Who Must Not Be Named
我们家庭小精灵的生活简直是猪狗不如
We house elves were treated like vermin sir
当然多比现在的生活还是猪狗不如
Of course Dobby is still treated like vermin
你为什么要穿那种东西 多比
Why do you wear that thing Dobby
这个吗
This sir
这是家庭小精灵的奴隶标志
It is a mark of the house elf's enslavement
只有主人送衣服给多比时多比才能自由
Dobby can only be freed if his master presents him with clothes
听我说
Listen
霍格沃茨即将发生恐怖的事情
Terrible things are about to happen at Hogwarts
哈利波特
Harry Potter
绝对不可以留在这个地方
must not stay here
因为历史即将就要重演了
now that history is to repeat itself
历史重演
Repeat itself
你是说以前也发生过这些事
You mean this has happened before
我不应该说这些的
I shouldn't have said that
坏多比 坏
Bad Dobby Bad
多比
Dobby
坏多比别这样 多比
Stop it Stop it Dobby
告诉我 多比
Tell me
以前什么时候发生过
When did this happen before
是谁在主使
Who's doing it now
多比不能说
Dobby cannot say sir
多比只希望哈利波特能够平安
Dobby only wants Harry Potter to be safe
不 多比告诉我 到底是谁
No Dobby Tell me Who is it
把他放这儿
Put him here
发生什么事了
What happened
又发生了攻击事件
There's been another attack
我想
I think
他应该是被石化了庞芮夫人
he's been Petrified Madam Pomfrey
或许
Look Perhaps
柯林是正要帮攻击者照相吧
he managed to take a picture of his attacker
这是怎么回事 阿不思
What can this mean Albus
这表示
It means
我们的学生面临极大的危险
that our students are in great danger
我该怎么告诉其他人
What should I tell the staff
说实话
The truth
告诉他们霍格沃茨
Tell them Hogwarts
已经不再安全了
is no longer safe
就如同我们所害怕的
It is as we feared Minerva
学校的密室已经再度被打开了
The Chamber of Secrets has indeed been opened again
再度 你是说
Again You mean
密室以前曾经被打开过
the Chamber of Secrets has been opened before
当然
Of course
你还不懂吗
Don't you see
一定是马尔福卢修斯
Lucius Malfoy
在这里读书的时候打开的
must have opened it when he was at school here
然后他又教马尔福怎么开
Now he's taught Draco how to do it
大概吧
Maybe
我们得等变身水完成后才能去确认
We'll have to wait for the Polyjuice Potion to know for sure
麻烦告诉我
Enlighten me
为什么我们要在大白天熬制变身水
Why are we brewing this potion in broad daylight
而且还在女厕所里面制作
in the middle of the girls' lavatory
你不怕被抓吗
Don't you think we'll get caught
不会的
No
不会有人进来这里
No one ever comes in here
为什么
Why
爱哭鬼默特尔
Moaning Myrtle
谁
Who
爱哭鬼默特尔
Moaning Myrtle
谁是爱哭鬼默特尔
Who's Moaning Myrtle
我就是爱哭鬼默特尔
I'm Moaning Myrtle
我不期待你听过我
I wouldn't expect you to know me
谁会谈论那个又丑
Who would ever talk about ugly
又悲惨
miserable
又闷闷不乐的爱哭鬼默特尔
moping Moaning Myrtle
她有点多愁善感
She's a little sensitive
大家过来
Gather round
快点
过来大家都看得到我吗
Can everybody see me
大家都 听得见吗
Can you all hear me
很好
Excellent
根据最近这几周所发生的可怕事件
In light of the dark events of recent weeks
邓不利多教授特许我成立这个小小的决斗社
Professor Dumbledore has granted me permission to start this Dueling Club
让我训练大家
to train you all up
等有需要的时候
in case you ever need
各位就能保护自己了
to defend yourselves
就像我以前做过的无数次自我防御
as I myself have done on countless occasions
想知道细节请参考我所有的著作
For full details see my published works
让我为各位介绍我的助手
Let me introduce my assistant
斯内普教授
Professor Snape
他愿意冒险来为我做一场小小的示范
He has sportingly agreed to help with a short demonstration
我可不想你们这些孩子担心
I don't want any of you youngsters to worry
我绝对不会伤害你们的魔药学教授
You'll still have your Potions master when I'm through with him
不要害怕
Never fear
一
One
二
Two
三
Three
去去 武器走
Expelliarmus
他有没有怎样
Do you think he's all right
谁理他
Who cares
这真是非常棒的想法
An excellent idea to show them that
斯内普教授你别介意我这么说
Professor Snape but if you don't mind me saying
这实在 太明显了
it was pretty obvious
我一眼就看出你的企图
what you were about to do
如果我要阻止你的话
If I had wanted to stop you
那简直是易如反掌
it would have been only too easy
或许我们能先教导学生
Perhaps it would be prudent to first teach the students
如何阻挡有恶意的咒语那应该会更有帮助
to block unfriendly spells
教授
professor
这建议太棒了 斯内普教授
An excellent suggestion Professor Snape
我们先找自愿者做示范
Let's have a volunteer pair
波特 韦斯莱 你们来怎么样
Potter Weasley how about you
韦斯莱的魔杖连使用最简单的魔咒都会出事
Weasley's wand causes devastation with the simplest spells
万一伤了波特还得把他送到医护室
We'll be sending Potter to the hospital wing in a matchbox
请容我推荐我学院的学生
Might I suggest someone from my own house
马尔福
Malfoy
好吗
perhaps
祝你好运 波特
Good luck Potter
谢谢
Thank you sir
各就各位
Wands at the ready
你害怕了吗 波特
Scared Potter
才怪
You wish
听我数到三
On the count of three
就开始解除对方的武装
cast your charms to disarm your opponent
只能够
Only
解除武装
to disarm
我们可不希望这里出任何意外
We don't want any accidents here
一
One
二
Two
为提司塔踢
Everte Statum
哩吐三卜啦
Rictusempra
我说过只能解除武装
I said disarm only
看我的蛇蛇攻
Serpensortia
不要动 波特
Don' t move Potter
我来帮你除掉它
I'll get rid of it for you
让我来吧 斯内普教授
Allow me Professor Snape
瓦拉太 阿蛇德哩
Alarte Ascendare
走开
离开他
蛇蛇 哎唯尼斯卡
Vipera Evanesca
你刚刚是在干嘛
What are you playing at
你是个爬说者
You' re a Parselmouth
你怎么都没告诉我们
Why didn't you tell us
我是什么
I'm a what
你可以跟蛇交谈
You can talk to snakes
我知道 我
I know I
我曾经在动物园放出一条蟒蛇吓倒了我的表哥达力
accidentally set a python on my cousin Dudley at the zoo once
就那一次
Once
那又怎样
But so what
我打赌这里很多人都做得到
I bet loads of people here can do it
不 没人做得到
No they can't
这不是一般的天赋 哈利
It's not a very common gift Harry
有不好的意义
This is bad
怎么不好
What's bad
如果不是我叫那条蛇
If I hadn't told that snake
不要攻击贾斯汀的话 那它
not to attack Justin
你是跟它说这个
That's what you said to it
你也在 你应该有听到
You were there You heard me
我听到你在说爬说语
I heard you speaking Parseltongue
那是蛇的语言
Snake language
我说了另外一种语言
I spoke a different language
可是我不懂
But I didn't realize
我为什么会说
How can I speak a language
我不知道的语言
without knowing I can
我也不知道 听起来就像是
I don't know but it sounded like
你在叫那条蛇去做什么事
you were egging the snake on or something
哈利 听我说
Harry listen to me
斯莱特林的象徵标志是蛇
There's a reason the symbol of Slytherin house is a serpent
那是因为萨拉札斯莱特林是个爬说嘴
Salazar Slytherin was a Parselmouth
他也可以跟蛇交谈
He could talk to snakes too
没错
Exactly
现在整个学校都开始以为
Now the whole school's gonna think
你是他的曾曾曾曾孙了
you're his great great great grandson
可是我不是
But I'm not
不可能是我
I can't be
他是一千年前的人
He lived a thousand years ago
根据目前的了解
For all we know
你很有可能就是
you could be
待会交谊厅见
I'll see you back in the common room
我要血
I want blood
他们都得死
They all must die
杀戮
Kill
杀戮时间到了
Time to kill
当场被逮到
Caught in the act
这一次我要你待不下去 波特
I'll have you out this time Potter
你记住我的话
Mark my words
不 飞七
No Mr Filch
你 你不懂
You you don't understand
教授
Professor
我发誓不是我做的
I swear I didn't
这已经不是我所能处理的了 波特
This is out of my hands Potter
邓不利多教授正在等你
Professor Dumbledore will be waiting for you
雪宝柠檬
Sherbet Lemon
邓不利多教授
Professor Dumbledore
你在想什么 波特
Bee in your bonnet Potter
我
I
我只是在想
I was just wondering
你到底有没有把我分对学院
if you put me in the right house
没错
Yes
你是特别难以分对
You were particularly difficult to place
可是我还是坚持我原先的看法
But I stand by what I said last year
你在斯莱特林会有所成就
you would have done well in Slytherin
你错了
you're wrong
哈利
Harry
教授
Professor
你的鸟
your bird
我什么都没做
There was nothing I could do
它突然全身都着火了
He just caught fire
也该是时候了
And about time too
它这几天看来糟透了
He's been looking dreadful for days
可惜你到燃烧日才见到它
Pity you had to see him on a burning day
福克斯 是一只凤凰 哈利
Fawkes is a phoenix Harry
凤凰在死亡的时候会化成火焰
They burst into flame when it is time for them to die
然后它们
and then they are
会在灰烬中重生
reborn from the ashes
凤凰真是迷人的生物
Fascinating creatures phoenixes
它们载得动
They can carry
比它重的多的东西
immensely heavy loads
而且它们的眼泪可以治病
Their tears have healing powers
邓不利多教授
Professor Dumbledore sir
等等
Wait
听我说
Listen
邓不利多教授
Professor Dumbledore sir
绝对不是哈利
it wasn't Harry
海格
Hagrid
如果有需要我可以到魔法部帮他做证
I'd be prepared to swear it in front of the Ministry of Magic
海格
Hagrid
不要紧张
Relax
我不相信
I do not believe
哈利他会攻击任何人
that Harry attacked anyone
你当然不会
Of course you don't
对呀
Right Well I'll
我出去外面等你们
I'll just wait outside then
好
yes
你不认为那是我做的 教授
you don't think it was me professor
没错 哈利
No Harry
我从不认为会是你
I do not think it was you
可是我要问你
But I must ask you
有没有什么事情想告诉我的
is there something you wish to tell me
没有 教授
No sir
没有
Nothing
好吧
Very well then
你可以走了
Off you go
一切都准备好了
Everything's set
只要加点要变的对象的一部分东西进去就可以了
We just need a bit of who you're changing into
克拉克跟高尔
Crabbe and Goyle
同时我们还得注意
We also need to make sure
真正的克拉克和高尔
that the real Crabbe and Goyle
在我们质问马尔福的时候不会忽然出现
can't burst in on us while we're interrogating Malfoy
怎么做
How
我通通都想好了
I've got it all worked out
我在这里加了点安眠药水
I filled these with a simple Sleeping Draught
简单但非常有效
Simple but powerful
现在等他们睡着了
Now once they're asleep
把他们藏到飞天扫帚柜
hide them in the broomstick cupboard
再拔他们几根头发
and pull out a few of their hairs
穿他们的制服
and put on their uniforms
那你要去拔谁的头发
Whose hair are you ripping out then
我早就准备好了
I've already got mine
米莉森布洛德
Millicent Bulstrode
斯莱特林的学生
Slytherin
我从她长袍上拿下来的
I got this off her robes
我去看看变身水怎么样了
I'm going to go check on the Polyjuice Potion
一定要让克拉克和高尔看到这个
Make sure that Crabbe and Goyle find these
罗恩 或许 该让我来
Ron maybe I should do it
喔 好吧
Yeah Right
温加癫啦唯啊萨
Wingardium Leviosa
酷
Cool
蠢得有水平
How thick could you get
快 动手
Come on let's get them
变身一个小时后
We'll have exactly one hour
我们就会恢复原状
before we change back into ourselves
头发放进去
Add the hairs
要喝克拉克的一部份
Essence of Crabbe
干杯
Cheers
我快要吐了
I think I'm gonna be sick
我也是
Me too
哈利
Harry
罗恩
Ron
我的老天啊
Bloody hell
我们的声音还是没有变
We still sound like ourselves
你必须装出克拉克的声音
You need to sound more like Crabbe
我的老天啊
Bloody hell
太好了
Excellent
赫敏呢
But where's Hermione
我
I
我想我不能去了
I don't think I'm going
你们两个先走吧
You go on without me
赫敏 你还好吧
Hermione are you okay
快走
Just go
你们别浪费时间
You're wasting time
走吧
Come on
斯莱特林的交谊厅应该在那边
I think the Slytherin common room's this way
好
Okay
你们两个
Excuse me
你怎么会
What are you doing
我是说 你怎么会在这里
I mean what are you doing down here
因为我是学院的级长
I happen to be a school prefect
反倒是你们这么晚了
you on the other hand
还在走道上游荡 想干什么
have no business wandering the corridors at night
你叫什么名字
What are your names again
我叫
I'm
克拉克 高尔
Crabbe Goyle
你们俩去哪了
where have you two been
这么晚了还要去大厅大吃大喝吗
Pigging out in the Great Hall all this time
干吗戴眼镜
Why are you wearing glasses
我在看书
Reading
看书
我不知道你还认识字
I didn't know you could read
那你在这里干什么 韦斯莱
And what are you doing down here Weasley
注意你讲话的态度 马尔福
Mind your attitude Malfoy
坐下
Well sit down
真看不出韦斯莱会是纯种
You'd never know the Weasleys were pure bloods
看他们的丢脸举动
the way they behave
他们让巫师世界蒙羞
They're an embarrassment to the wizarding world
全家都是
All of them
你是怎么了 克拉克
What's wrong with you Crabbe
我肚子痛
Stomachache
知道吗
you know
我真惊讶预言家日报
I'm surprised the Daily Prophet
竟然没有报道学校的攻击事件
hasn't done a report on all these attacks
我想一定是被邓不利多压下来
I suppose Dumbledore is trying to hush it all up
我爸总是说邓不利多是霍格沃茨
Father always said Dumbledore was the worst thing
有史以来最大的祸害
that ever happened to this place
才不是呢
You're wrong
什么
What
你是说
You think
还有人比邓不利多还要糟吗
there's someone here who's worse than Dumbledore
说啊 是不是
Well Do you
哈利波特啊
Harry Potter
说得好 高尔
Good one Goyle
你说得一点也没错
You're absolutely right
讨厌的波特
Saint Potter
大家竟然
And people
还把他当成斯莱特林的传人
actually think that he's the Heir of Slytherin
那你一定知道后面的主使者是谁
But then you must have some idea who's behind it all
你知道我不知道了 高尔 我昨天告诉过你了
You know I don't Goyle I told you yesterday
我到底要跟你说几次
How many times do I have to tell you
这是你的吗
Is this yours
可是我爸爸告诉过我
But my father did say this
密室在五十年前曾经被打开过
It's been 50 years since the Chamber was opened
他不肯说是谁打开的
He wouldn't tell me who opened it
只说他们被开除了
Only that they were expelled
上次密室被打开的时候
The last time the Chamber of Secrets was opened
有个麻种被杀了
a Mudblood died
所以这次密室被打开
So it's only a matter of time
迟早也会有麻种被杀掉
before one of them is killed this time
要我的话
As for me
我希望那是赫敏
I hope it's Granger
你们两个怎么回事
What's the matter with you two
你们今天有点怪怪的
you're acting very odd
因为他肚子痛
It's his stomachache
冷静点
Calm down
你的疤
Scar
头发
Hair
嘿 你们去哪里
Hey Where are you going
差点穿帮了
That was close
赫敏 快 我们有好多东西要告诉你
Hermione come out We've got loads to tell you
走开
Go away
你们自己去看
Wait till you see
真是糟糕透了
It's awful
赫敏 你没事吧
Hermione Are you okay
记不记得我跟你们说过
Do you remember me telling you
变身水只能用来变成人类
that the Polyjuice Potion was only for human transformations
我从米莉森布洛德身上拔出来的是猫的毛
It was cat hair I plucked off Millicent Bulstrode's robes
你们看看我的脸
Look at my face
你长尾巴了
Look at your tail
你跟赫敏谈过了吗
Have you spoken to Hermione
她还得在医院里面待几天
She should be out of hospital in a few days
直到她不再吐毛球出来
when she stops coughing up fur balls
这是什么
What's this
好恶心
Yuck
爱哭鬼默特尔的洗手间淹水了
Looks like Moaning Myrtle's flooded the bathroom
你也是来对我丢东西的吗
Come to throw something else at me
我为什么要对你丢东西
Why would I throw something at you
我怎么知道
Don't ask me
我正坐着 想着我自己的心事忽然就有人把东西丢到我身上
Here I am minding my own business and someone thinks it's funny to throw a book at me
对你丢东西应该没有关系吧
But it can't hurt if someone throws something at you
我是说
I mean
那些东西又打不到你
it'll just go right through you
大家想反正打不到我就拼命对我丢东西
Sure Let's all throw books at Myrtle because she can't feel it
穿过她的肚子可以得十分
Ten points if you get it through her stomach
穿过她的头可以得五十分
Fifty points if it goes through her head
到底是谁对你丢东西
But who threw it at you anyway
我不知道
I don't know
我没有看到人
I didn't see them
我刚好坐在马桶里面
I was just sitting in the U bend
思考着死亡
thinking about death
然后那个东西
and it fell
就从我头上穿过去了
through the top of my head
汤姆马佛鲁瑞斗
Tom Marvolo Riddle
我的名字叫做
My name
哈利
is Harry
波特
Potter
你好 哈利波特
我叫做汤姆瑞斗
你知道
Do you know anything
任何跟密室有关的事吗
about the Chamber of Secrets
知道
你能
Can you
告诉我吗
tell me
不行
可是我能让你亲自去看
让我带你回到五十年前
六月十三日
对不起
Excuse me
你能不能告诉我出了什么事
Could you tell me what's going on here
你是汤姆瑞斗
Are you Tom Riddle
你好 你听得到我吗
Hello can you hear me
瑞斗
Riddle
过来
Come
邓不利多教授
Professor Dumbledore
邓不利多
Dumbledore
这么晚还在外面游荡是非常不智的举动
It is not wise to be wandering around this late hour Tom
是 教授
Yes professor
我只是
I suppose I
我必须亲自看看谣言是不是真的
I had to see for myself if the rumors were true
恐怕是真的 汤姆那是真的
I'm afraid they are Tom They are true
学校的事也是吗
About the school as well
我已经无家可归了
I don't have a home to go to
他们不会真的关闭霍格沃茨吧 教授
They wouldn't really close Hogwarts would they professor
我都了解 汤姆
I understand Tom
但是
but I'm afraid
狄劈校长可能没有其他选择
Headmaster Dippet may have no choice
如果一切都停止
Sir if it all stopped
如果幕后的主使者能被捉到呢
if the person responsible was caught
你是不是
Is there something
有什么事想要跟我说呢
you wish to tell me
没有
No sir
没事
Nothing
那好吧
Very well then
你可以走了
Off you go
教授晚安
Good night sir
我们快走
Let's get you out of there
晚安 海格
Evening Hagrid
我不得不告发你了
I'm going to have to turn you in Hagrid
我知道你无意杀害任何人可是
I don't think you meant it to kill anyone
你不可以
You can't
你根本不懂
You don't understand
那个死去女孩的父母明天就会到了
The dead girl's parents will be here tomorrow
霍格沃茨唯一能为他们做的
The least Hogwarts can do
就是处决杀害他们女儿的凶手
is make sure the thing that killed their daughter is slaughtered
不是它做的
It wasn't him
阿辣哥绝对不会杀人不可能
Aragog never killed no one Never
怪兽是不能拿来当宠物的 海格
Monsters don't make good pets Hagrid
快让开 不要
Now stand aside No
快让开 海格
Stand aside Hagrid
不要
No
西放阿魁里昂
Cistem Aperio
阿拉尼亚艾特秘
Arania Exumai
阿辣哥
Aragog
我不能放你走
I can't let you go
你的行为让你失去学习资格 海格 你会被开除
They'll have your wand for this Hagrid You'll be expelled
海格
Hagrid
是海格做的
It was Hagrid
五十年前打开密室的人就是海格
Hagrid opened the Chamber of Secrets 50 years ago
不可能会是海格
It can't be Hagrid
这绝对不可能
It just can't be
我们根本不认识这个汤姆瑞斗
We don't even know this Tom Riddle
他听起来像个讨厌的告密鬼
He sounds like a dirty rotten snitch to me
那个怪兽杀了人 罗恩
The monster had killed somebody Ron
换成是我们会怎么做
What would any of us have done
听着 海格是我们的朋友
Look Hagrid's our friend
我们为什么不直接去间他
Why don't we just go and ask him about it
那谈话的气氛一定很好
That would be a cheerful visit
你好 海格
Hello Hagrid
告诉我们你最近有没有在学校
Tell us have you been setting anything
放出什么毛茸茸的怪物
mad and hairy loose in the castle lately
毛茸茸的怪物
Mad and hairy
你们该不会是在说我吧
You wouldn't be talking about me now would you
不是
No
你拿的是什么 海格
What's that you've got Hagrid
肉食蛞蝓杀虫剂
It's Flesh Eating Slug Repellent
曼德拉草要用的
For the Mandrakes you know
根据苗芽教授所说
Now according to Professor Sprout
它们还需要长一段时间 等它们被咬的地方都清干净了
they've still got a bit of growing up to do But once their acne's cleared up
我们就可以把曼德拉草剁一剁熬一熬
we'll be able to chop them up and stew them
然后医院里面那些被石化的人就可以恢复了
and then we'll get those people down at the hospital un Petrified
在这段期间呢
In the meantime though
你们三个
you three
最好能够乖一点
had best be looking after yourselves
好吗
All right
你好 纳威
Hello Neville
哈利 不知道谁干的
Harry I don't know who did it
你最好过去看一下
but you'd better come
快
Come on
一定是格兰芬多的学生
It had to be a Gryffindor
别的学院的人根本进不来
Nobody else knows our password
除非下手的人不是学生
Unless it wasn't a student
不管是谁
Whoever it was
他们一定在找什么东西
they must have been looking for something
那他们找到了
And they found it
汤姆瑞斗的日记不见了
Tom Riddle's diary is gone
听我说
All right listen up
大家全力以赴
We play our game
赫奇帕奇根本不是我们的对手
Hufflepuff doesn't stand a chance
我们比他们厉害 迅速又精明
We're stronger quicker and smarter
更别说他们害怕死了飞得太近
Not to mention they're dead scared that Harry will Petrify them
被哈利石化了
if they fly anywhere near him
喔 有道理
Well that too
麦格教授
Professor McGonagall
这场比赛取消了
This match has been canceled
怎么可以取消呢
We can't cancel Quidditch
冷静点 伍德
Silence Wood
你跟其他队员
You and your teammates
马上回到格兰芬多大楼 快
will go to Gryffindor Tower Now
波特 你跟我一块去找韦斯莱
Potter you and I will find Mr Weasley
有件事必须让你们两个知道
There's something the both of you have to see
先警告你们这件事可能会吓到你们
I warn you This could be a wee bit of a shock
赫敏
Hermione
她是在图书馆附近被发现的
She was found near the library
还带着这个
along with this
你们知道这镜子有什么意义吗
Does it mean anything to either of you
不知道
No
各位同学请注意
Could I have your attention please
基于近来发生的事件
Because of recent events
我们必须马上施行新的规定
these new rules will be put into effect immediately
每一个学生每晚都必须在六点前回到学院的交谊厅
All students will return to their house common rooms by 6:00 every evening
每位同学上课时
All students
都会有一位教授陪同前往
will be escorted to each lesson by a teacher
没有人可以例外
No exceptions
我必须告诉各位
I should tell you this
除非进行攻击的凶手被逮到
behind these attacks is caught Unless the culprit
否则就得关闭学校
it is likely the school will be closed
我们必须去跟海格谈谈
We've got to talk to Hagrid Ron
我绝不相信是他
I can't believe it's him
可是如果上次是他放怪兽出来的
but if he did set the monster loose last time
那他一定知道怎么进入密室
he'll know how to get inside the Chamber of Secrets
那就有头绪了
That's a start
可是麦格教授刚刚说
But you heard McGonagall
除非是去上课 否则不准离开
We're not allowed to leave the tower except for class
我想该把我爸爸的隐形斗篷拿出来用了
I think it's time to get my dad's old cloak out again
是谁
Who's there
有人吗
Hello
你拿那个干吗
What's that for
没事 我正在等
Nothing I was expecting
没什么
It doesn't matter
进来吧
Come on in
我刚泡了一壶茶
I just made a pot of tea
海格
Hagrid
你还好吧
are you okay
我很好
I'm fine
我没事
I'm all right
你有听说赫敏的事吗
Did you hear about Hermione
有 我已经听说了
Yeah I heard about that all right
听我说
Look
我们想问你一些事情
we have to ask you something
你知道是谁打开了密室的门吗
Do you know who's opened the Chamber of Secrets
你必须了解一件事
What you had to understand about that is
快 躲到斗篷里
Quick under the cloak
别出声 你们两个要保持安静
Don't say a word Be quiet both of you
邓不利多教授
Professor Dumbledore sir
晚安 海格
Good evening Hagrid
我是不是
I wonder
可以进去 当然了
could we Of course
请进 请进
Come in Come in
我爸爸的上司
That's Dad's boss
康尼留斯夫子
Cornelius Fudge
魔法部部长
Minister of Magic
老实说 海格
Bad business Hagrid
这个任务很棘手
very bad business
我非来不可
Had to come
三起麻瓜后代被攻击事件事情闹得太大
Three attacks on Muggle borns Things have gone far enough
魔法部必须有所行动
The Ministry's got to act
可是我没 你们知道我没有做
But I never you know I never professor
我希望你能够明白 夫子
I want it understood Cornelius
我对海格
that Hagrid
绝对的信任
has my full confidence
阿不思 你听我说
Albus look
海格的纪录对他很不利 我必须带他走
Hagrid's record is against him I've got to take him
带我走 去哪儿
Take me Take me where
不会是阿兹卡班吧
Not Azkaban prison
我没有选择的余地了 海格
I'm afraid we have no choice Hagrid
夫子 你已经来了
Already here Fudge
很好
Good
你来这儿干什么
What are you doing here
快滚出我的房子
Get out of my house
相信我
Believe me
我一点也不想走进你的这个
I take absolutely no pleasure being inside your
这叫房子吗
you call this a house
我只是有事到学校
I simply called up the school
而他们告诉我校长在这里
and was told the headmaster was here
你到学校里去找我有什么事情呢
Well what exactly is it that you want with me
我还有其他的理事都认为
The other governors and I have decided
该是你走的时候了
it's time for you to step aside
这是你的停职令
This is an order of suspension
上头有全部十二名理事的签名
You'll find all 1 2 signatures on it
我们都觉得你似乎越来越糊涂
I'm afraid we feel you've rather lost your touch
攻击事件再继续下去
Well what with all these attacks
霍格沃茨的麻瓜后代很快就死光了
there'll be no Muggle borns left at Hogwarts
你想想这会是我们学校多大的损失
I can only imagine what an awful loss that would be to the school
你们不能把校长免职
you can't take Professor Dumbledore away
他离开后麻瓜后代就一点希望都没有了
Take him away and the Muggle borns won't stand a chance
记住我的话 一定会有人再被杀掉的
You mark my words there'll be killings next
你是这样想的吗
You think so
海格 冷静一点
Calm yourself Hagrid
如果理事们都希望我离职
If the governors desire my removal
那么我当然
I will of course
应该走了
step aside
可是
However
只要霍格沃茨有人发出求救信号
you will find that help will always be given at Hogwarts
必定会有人
to those who
伸出援手
ask for it
真是令人感动
Admirable sentiments
请吧
Shall we
夫子
Fudge
走吧 海格
Come Hagrid
走啊
Well
如果
If
如果有人需要找什么东西的话
If anybody was looking for some stuff
他们唯一需要做的
then all they'd have to do would be
就是跟着蜘蛛走
to follow the spiders
没错
Yep
蜘蛛会引导他们
That would lead them right
这就是我想要说的
That's all I have to say
哦 对了 我还需要有人帮我喂喂牙牙
Oh and someone will need to feed Fang while I'm away
再见了
Good boy
海格说得没错
Hagrid's right
如果邓不利多离开
With Dumbledore gone
每天都会有攻击发生的
there'll be an attack a day
你看
Look
走吧
Come on
来 牙牙
Come on Fang
走
Come on
去哪儿
What
你没听到海格说的话吗
You heard what Hagrid said
跟着蜘蛛走
Follow the spiders
他们往禁忌森林去了
They're heading to the Dark Forest
为什么是蜘蛛
Why spiders
为什么
Why
他就不是说跟着蝴蝶走呢
couldn't it be "follow the butterflies"
哈利我不喜欢这样
Harry I don't like this
哈利 我真的很不喜欢这样
Harry I don't like this at all
我们可不可以回去
Can we go back now
快来
Come on
是谁来啦
Who is it
不要惊慌
Don't panic
海格
Hagrid
是你吗
Is that you
我们是海格的朋友
We're friends of Hagrid's
你
And you
你是阿辣哥 对不对
You're Aragog aren't you
是的
Yes
海格从没让人来过我们这里
Hagrid has never sent men into our hollow before
海格有麻烦了
He's in trouble
学校里面发生了一些攻击事件
Up at the school there have been attacks
他们说那是海格做的
They think it's Hagrid
他们认为海格又再一次的打开了密室
They think he opened the Chamber of Secrets Like before
那不是真的
That's a lie
海格没有打开过密室的门
Hagrid never opened the Chamber of Secrets
那么你不是那个怪兽了
Then you're not the monster
没错
No
怪兽是在这城堡里诞生的
The monster was born in the castle
但我是被一个旅行者放在口袋里从遥远的地方带来的
I came to Hagrid from a distant land in the pocket of a traveler
哈利 不要吵
Harry
如果你不是怪兽
But if you're not the monster
那五十年前是谁杀了那个女孩
then what did kill that girl 50 years ago
我们绝口不提那个东西
We do not speak of it
那是我们蜘蛛最害怕的一种非常古老的动物
It is an ancient creature we spiders fear above all others
你看过那个动物吗
But have you seen it
我从来没见过城堡其他角落
but the box in which Hagrid kept me
海格只把我放在一个箱子里养
I never saw any part of the castle
那个死去的女孩
The girl
是在厕所被发现的
was discovered in a bathroom
当他们指控我时
When I was accused
海格就把我带到这里
Hagrid brought me here
哈利 干嘛
Harry What
没事了
Well
谢谢你
thank you
那我们走了
We'll just go
走
Go
恐怕不行
I think not
我的子女们
My sons and daughters
因为我的命令而不伤害海格
do not harm Hagrid on my command
但是当有新鲜的肉自己送上门来的时候
But I cannot deny them fresh meat
我可不能再阻止它们了
when it wanders so willingly into our midst
再见 海格的朋友
Goodbye friend of Hagrid
现在我们可以害怕了吗
Can we panic now
有什么咒语可以用的
Know any spells
有一个
One
可是力量不够对付所有的蜘蛛
but it's not powerful enough for all of them
为什么需要赫敏的时候她偏不在
Where's Hermione when you need her
我们快走
Let's go
阿拉哇爱惜马特
Arania Exumai
开车
Go
真高兴我们出来
Glad we're out of there
阿拉哇
Arania
爱惜马特
Exumai
谢谢了
Thanks for that
不客气
Don't mention it
赶快离开这里
Get us out of here
快
Now
快啊 快点 开快点
Come on Come on move faster
快点 走
Come on Go
快点飞起来
Get us in the air
飞行引擎卡住了
The flying gear's jammed
加油
Come on Pull
我在努力
I'm trying
跟着蜘蛛走
Follow the spiders
等海格从阿兹卡班回来以后
If Hagrid ever gets out of Azkaban
我要杀了他
I'll kill him
他要我们到那里面去究竟是为了什么
I mean what was the point of sending us in there
我们有查出什么吗
What have we found out
我们知道了一件事
We know one thing
密室不是被海格打开的
Hagrid never opened the Chamber of Secrets
他是无辜的
He was innocent
真希望你能好起来 赫敏
Wish you were here Hermione
我们需要你
We need you
真的很需要你
Now more than ever
那是什么
What's that
罗恩
Ron
这就是赫敏会在图书馆附近遭到攻击的原因
This is why Hermione was in the library the day she was attacked
快走
Come on
在我们国土漫游的众多可怕怪兽中
Of the many fearsome beasts that roam our land
最危险的就是蛇怪
none is more deadly than the basilisk
它们可拥有数百年的寿命
Capable of living for hundreds of years
任何与蛇怪眼睛接触的人都会马上死去
instant death awaits any who meet this giant serpent's eye
蜘蛛将闻风窜逃
Spiders flee before it
罗恩 就是这个
Ron this is it
密室里面的那个怪兽就是蛇怪
The monster in the Chamber of Secrets is a basilisk
难怪我听到的那个声音
That's why I can hear it speak
是来自一条蛇
It's a snake
可是如果看了它的眼睛就会死
But if it kills by looking people in the eye
那为什么没有人死呢
why is it no one's dead
因为没有人看到它的眼睛
Because no one did look it in the eye
至少没有直接看到
Not directly at least
柯林是透过照相机看到的
Colin saw it through his camera
贾斯汀 贾斯汀一定是从尼克爵士后面
Justin Justin must have seen the basilisk
穿过去看到的
through Nearly Headless Nick
尼克则是直接看到蛇怪
Nick got the full blast of it
可是他早就死了他无法再死一次
But he's a ghost he couldn't die again
至于赫敏
And Hermione
是那面镜子
had the mirror
她一定是要用镜子探照角落
I bet you she was using it to look around corners
预防蛇怪出现
in case it came along
诺里斯太太呢
And Mrs Norris
她肯定没有拿照相机
I'm pretty sure she didn't have a camera
或镜子什么的 哈利
or a mirror Harry
是水 那天晚上地板上有水
The water There was water on the floor that night
诺里斯太太是看到蛇怪的倒影
She only saw the basilisk's reflection
蜘蛛将闻风窜逃
Spiders flee before it
这一切都符合
It all fits
那蛇怪是怎么到处活动的
But how's a basilisk been getting around
一条恶心的绿色大蛇不可能不被发现
A dirty great snake Someone would have seen it
赫敏也想出答案了
Hermione's answered that too
水管
Pipes
它是利用管线系统
It's using the plumbing
你还记得阿辣哥说的
Remember what Aragog said
五十年前死去的那个女孩吗
about that girl 50 years ago
她是在厕所死的
She died in a bathroom
如果她一直没走呢
What if she never left
爱哭鬼默特尔
Moaning Myrtle
所有学生
All students
请马上回到学院寝室去
are to return to their house dormitories at once
所有的教授请到二楼走廊集合
All teachers to the second floor corridor immediately
大家都看到了
As you can see
斯莱特林的传人
the Heir of Slytherin
又再一次留下了讯息
has left another message
我们最深的恐惧就要成真
Our worst fear has been realized
一个学生被怪兽抓走
A student has been taken by the monster
带进了密室里面
into the Chamber itself
必须马上把所有学生送回家
The students must be sent home
霍格沃茨恐怕得永远关闭了
I'm afraid this is the end of Hogwarts
抱歉 睡过头了
So sorry Dozed off
没错过什么吧
What have I missed
有个学生被怪兽抓走了 洛克哈特
A girl has been snatched by the monster Lockhart
你表现的机会终于来了
Your moment has come at last
表 表现
My moment
你昨天晚上不是说过
Weren't you saying just last night
你一直都知道
that you've known all along
密室的入口在哪里吗
where the entrance to the Chamber of Secrets is
那好啊
That's settled
就麻烦你一个人去对付那个怪兽 吉尔德罗伊
We'll leave you to deal with the monster Gilderoy
毕竟我们从没看过你大展身手
Your skills after all are legend
没问题
Very well
那我先回我办公室去
I'll just be in my office getting
准备一下
Getting ready
那个怪兽到底把谁抓走了
Who is it that the monster's taken Minerva
金妮韦斯莱
Ginny Weasley
她的骨骸将永远躺在密室里
Her skeleton will lie in the Chamber forever
金妮
Ginny
洛克哈特或许很没用
Lockhart may be useless
可是他现在正打算进入密室
but he's going to try and get into the Chamber
至少我们去把我们知道的一切告诉他
At least we can tell him what we know
教授我们有一些事情要告诉你
Professor we have some information for you
你要离开这里吗
Are you going somewhere
呃 是啊
Well yes
我有急事
Urgent call
我非走不可 我得走
Unavoidable Got to go
那我妹妹她怎么办
What about my sister
呃 关于这件不幸的事
Well As to that most unfortunate
没有人比我更悲痛了
No one regrets more than I
你是我们黑魔法防御学的教授
You're the Defense Against the Dark Arts teacher
你不能就这样走
You can't go now
我必须说当我接受这个工作的时候
I must say when I took the job
工作内容里面并没有说到
there was nothing in the description
你打算逃走
You're running away
可是你的书把你说得那么伟大
After all you did in your books
那是误会
Books can be misleading
那是你写的啊 拜托
You wrote them
你们用一下你们的常识好吗
My dear boy do use your common sense
如果不让人们相信我书中经历
My books wouldn't have sold half as well
我的书哪会卖得这么好
if people didn't think I'd done those things
你是个骗子
You're a fraud
你只是把别的巫师的英雄事迹揽在自己身上
You've been taking credit for what other wizards have done
你总会一些什么法术吧
Is there anything you can do
没错
Yes
既然你都这么问了
now you mention it
我的记忆符咒还蛮强的
I'm rather gifted with Memory Charms
不然那些巫师
Otherwise all those wizards
岂不是会来跟我罗嗦了
would have gone blabbing
这样我的书就没有说服力了
I'd never have sold another book
事实上
In fact
我也要让你们失忆
I'm going to have to do the same to you
你连想都不要想
Don't even think about it
是谁
Who's there
哈利 你好
Hello Harry
你来做什么
What do you want
我来问你 你是怎么死的
To ask you how you died
那真的很可怕
It was dreadful
一切就在这里发生就在这间厕所里面
It happened right here in this very cubicle
因为奥利夫霍恩比取笑我的眼镜所以我躲在这里
I'd hidden because Olive Hornby was teasing me about my glasses
我正在哭
I was crying
突然就听到有人走进来
and then I heard somebody come in
那是谁 默特尔
Who was it Myrtle
我不知道
I don't know
我正在难过
I was distraught
可是他们说了一些奇怪的东西
But they said something funny
好像是种什么语言
a kind of made up language
我马上听出是个男孩的声音
And I realized it was a boy
所以我把门打开
so I unlocked the door
准备叫他走开
to tell him to go away
然后我就死了
and I died
就这样吗
Just like that
怎么会
How
我只记得我看到了一双好大的黄眼珠
I just remember seeing a pair of great big yellow eyes
就在那个洗脸槽里
over there by that sink
就是这儿了
This is it
没错 罗恩
This is it Ron
我想这一定就是密室的入口
I think this is the entrance to the Chamber of Secrets
说点什么
Say something
哈利 用爬说语说话
Harry say something in Parseltongue
太棒了 哈利
Excellent Harry
做得好
Good work
这样我就放心了
Well then I'll just be
这里应该不需要我了
There's no need for me to stay
这里很需要你
Yes there is
你先下去
You first
让我先下去有什么好处
Now boys what good will it do
总比我们先下去好
Better you than us
但是 显然是这样的
But Obviously yes
你们真的不想先下去
Sure you don't want to test it first
这下面真的好脏
It's really quite filthy down here
好了
All right
我们下去
Let's go
喔 哈利
Oh Harry
如果你死在下面的话
If you die down there
我很欢迎你共用我的厕所
you're welcome to share my toilet
谢了 默特尔
Thanks Myrtle
记住
Now remember
一听到任何动静
Any sign of movement
马上闭上你的眼睛
close your eyes straightaway
走啊
Go on
这边
This way
这是什么
What's this
这看起来很像
It looks like
蛇
a snake
这是蛇的皮
It's a snakeskin
天啊
Bloody hell
这条蛇大概有六十尺长吧
Whatever shed this must be 60 feet long
可能不只
Or more
他的胆子还真大
Heart of a lion this one
冒险结束了 孩子们
The adventure ends here boys
但是不要着急 全世界
But don't fret The world
都会知道这个故事
will know our story
我如何因为晚了一步而救不了那女孩
How I was too late to save the girl
你们两个又如何
How you two
因为看到她的尸体过于悲伤而失去记忆
tragically lost your minds at the sight of her mangled body
好
So
你先吧 波特
you first Mr Potter
跟你的记忆说再见吧
Say goodbye to your memories
空空 遗忘
Obliviate
哈利
Harry
罗恩
Ron
罗恩 你没事吧
Ron are you okay
我没事
I'm fine
嗨
Hello
你是谁啊
Who are you
罗恩韦斯莱
Ron Weasley
真的
Really
那我是谁啊
And who am I
洛克哈特的记忆咒反弹回去
Lockhart's Memory Charm backfired
他连自己是谁都忘了
He hasn't got a clue who he is
这里真是一个奇怪的地方
It's an odd sort of place isn't it
你住这儿
Do you live here
不是
No
真的
Really
我现在要做什么
What do I do now
你留在这里把石头搬开
you wait here and try and shift some of this rock
这样等我们回来就可以通过
so we can get back through
我现在要去找金妮
I'll go on and find Ginny
好
Okay
金妮
Ginny
金妮 你千万不能死
Ginny please don't be dead
快醒醒 醒醒 求求你快醒醒
Wake up wake up Please wake up
她醒不了了
She won't wake
汤姆
Tom
汤姆瑞斗
Tom Riddle
你说她醒不了了是什么意思
What do you mean she won't wake
她还 她还活着
She's not She's still alive
但醒不了
but only just
你是鬼吗
Are you a ghost
记忆
A memory
我是留存在日记中五十年的记忆
preserved in a diary for 50 years
她就跟冰块一样冷
She's cold as ice
金妮 求求你别死
Ginny please don't be dead
快醒来
Wake up
你必须帮帮我 汤姆
You've got to help me Tom
这里头有蛇怪
There's a basilisk
它受到召唤才会出现
It won't come until it's called
把我的魔杖给我
Give me my wand Tom
你不会需要它的
You won't be needing it
我们要赶快离开 我们必须救她
We've got to go We've got to save her
我恐怕帮不了你了
I'm afraid I can't do that
你要知道当可怜的金妮变得越弱
You see as poor Ginny grows weaker
我就变得更强
I grow stronger
没错 哈利
Yes Harry
就是金妮韦斯莱
it was Ginny Weasley
打开了密室的门
who opened the Chamber of Secrets
不 不会是她 不可能是她
No She couldn't She wouldn't
是金妮放出蛇怪攻击那些麻种以及爆竹的猫
It was Ginny who set the basilisk on the Mudbloods and Filch's cat
也是她在墙上留下那些恐吓讯息
Ginny who wrote the threatening messages on the walls
为什么
But why
是我要她这么做的
Because I told her to
你会慢慢发现 我很有说服力
You'll find I can be very persuasive
当然金妮并不知自己做了什么
Not that she knew what she was doing
不过她从各种迹象猜出来了
She was shall we say in a kind of trance
日记的力量把她给吓坏了
Still the power of the diary began to scare her
于是她试着把日记丢到女厕所
She tried to dispose of it in the girls' bathroom
而后来
And then
谁得到了日记呢
who should find it
当然是你喽
But you
因为你是我最急切想见面的人
the very person I was most anxious to meet
你为什么那么急着想要见我
And why did you want to meet me
我必须得跟你谈谈
I knew I had to talk to you
我必须见你一面
meet you if I could
所以我决定把我逮到那个蠢汉海格的经过让你看一看
So I decided to show you my capture of that brainless oaf Hagrid
以赢取你的信任
to gain your trust
海格是我的朋友
Hagrid's my friend
你陷害了他 对不对
And you framed him didn't you
我的说法跟海格的不同
It was my word against Hagrid's
只有邓不利多
Only Dumbledore
才相信他是无辜的
seemed to think he was innocent
邓不利多也看穿了你的谎言
I'll bet Dumbledore saw right through you
从那之后他就很令人厌烦的监视着我
He certainly kept an annoyingly close watch on me after that
在我还待在学校的时候再打开密室 实在是太冒险了
I knew it wouldn't be safe to open the Chamber again while I was still at school
所以我决定留下我的日记
so I decided to leave behind a diary
把十六岁的我保存在日记里头
preserving my 1 6 year old self in its pages
直到有一天
so that one day
我能够引导另一个人来完成
I would be able to lead another
萨拉札斯莱特林的伟大使命
to finish Salazar Slytherin's noble work
可是这次你并没有完成任何使命
Well you haven't finished it this time
再过几个小时
In a few hours
曼德拉草药就完成了
the Mandrake Draught will be ready
被石化的那些人
And everyone who was Petrified
马上就会醒过来了
will be all right again
我没告诉过你吗
Haven't I told you
杀掉麻种对我来说已经没那么重要
Killing Mudbloods doesn't matter to me anymore
这几个月来 我的新目标就是你
For many months now my new target has been you
我不懂为什么一个没什么魔法天赋的婴儿
How is it that a baby with no extraordinary magical talent
竟然可以打败
was able to defeat
有史以来最伟大的巫师
the greatest wizard of all time
你是如何逃生 除了个伤疤毫发无损
How did you escape with nothing but a scar
而佛地魔的力量却被摧毁了
while Lord Voldemort's powers were destroyed
你干嘛那么关心我如何逃生
Why do you care how I escaped
佛地魔又不是你那个时代的人
Voldemort was after your time
佛地魔
Voldemort
就是我的过去
is my past
现在 还有未来
present and future
汤姆马佛鲁瑞斗
我是佛地魔
你 你就是斯莱特林的传人
You you're the Heir of Slytherin
你就是佛地魔
You're Voldemort
当然 你该不会认为
Surely you didn't think
我会继续留着
I was going to keep
我那肮脏麻瓜父亲的姓吧
my filthy Muggle father's name
绝不会
No
我为自己取了新名字
I fashioned myself a new name
我知道当我成为全世界最伟大的魔法师后
a name I knew wizards everywhere would one day fear to speak
整个巫师世界将会害怕提到这个名字
when I became the greatest sorcerer in the world
阿不思邓布利多
Albus Dumbledore
他才是全世界最伟大的魔法师
is the greatest sorcerer in the world
我不过是凭着一点记忆
Dumbledore's been driven out of
就把邓不利多给赶走了
this castle by the mere memory of me
他不会离开的
He'll never be gone
因我们仍然有人对他表示忠诚
Not as long as those who remain are loyal to him
福克斯
Fawkes
原来这就是邓不利多
So this is what Dumbledore
送给他拥护者的东西
sends his great defender
一只鸟
A songbird
跟一顶破帽子
and an old hat
让我们展现佛地魔王的力量
Let's match the power of Lord Voldemort
由斯莱特林传人对抗出名的
Heir of Salazar Slytherinagainst the famous
哈利波特
Harry Potter
你的爬说语救不了你的 哈利
Parseltongue won't save you now Potter
它只听我的命令
It only obeys me
不
No
你的凤凰或许可以弄瞎蛇怪
your bird may have blinded the basilisk
但是蛇怪还是可以听得到你
but it can still hear you
没错 哈利
Yes Potter
整个过程就快完成了
The process is nearly complete
再过几分钟 金妮韦斯莱就会死了
In a few minutes Ginny Weasley will be dead
而我不再只是个记忆
and I will cease to be a memory
佛地魔王即将回来
Lord Voldemort will return
而且充满生命力
very much alive
金妮
Ginny
很神奇 是不是
Remarkable isn't it
蛇怪的毒液侵入人体的速度果然十分迅速
how quickly the venom of the basilisk penetrates the body
我想你大概只剩下几分钟好活
I'd guess you have little more than a minute to live
你很快就会去陪你的麻种母亲 哈利
You'll be with your dear Mudblood mother soon Harry
真好笑
Funny
一本书就能造成这么大的伤害
the damage a silly little book can do
尤其
especially
拿到它的人还是个傻女孩
in the hands of a silly little girl
你做什么
What are you doing
住手 不可以
Stop No
金妮
Ginny
哈利
Harry
是我做的
It was me
可是我发誓
But I swear
我不是故意的
I didn't mean to
瑞斗害我的
Riddle made me
还有
and
哈利 你受伤了
Harry you're hurt
别担心
Don't worry
金妮
Ginny
你必须想办法先出去
you need to get yourself out
顺着密道走
Follow the Chamber
你就会遇到罗恩了
and you'll find Ron
你真的很棒 福克斯
You were brilliant Fawkes
我的行动还不够快
I just wasn't quick enough
对了
Of course
凤凰的眼泪可以治病
Phoenix tears have healing powers
谢了
Thanks
没事了 金妮
It's all right Ginny
全结束了
It's over
那只是个回忆而已
It's just a memory
太神奇了
Amazing
这好像魔法
This is just like magic
你们两位一定明白
You both realize of course
在过去的这几个小时里
that in the past few hours
你们已违反了将近几十条校规
you have broken perhaps a dozen school rules
是 校长
Yes sir
这足以让学校把你们开除
There is sufficient evidence to have you both expelled
是 校长
Yes sir
你们的所作所为
Therefore it is only fitting
也足以让你们得到
that you both receive
霍格沃茨的特殊贡献奖
Special Awards for Services to the School
谢谢你 校长
Thanks sir
好了 韦斯莱同学
Now Mr Weasley
麻烦请猫头鹰
if you would have an owl
把这封文件送到阿兹卡班
deliver these release papers to Azkaban
我想
I believe
也该请我们的猎场管理人回来了
we want our gamekeeper back
哈利
Harry
首先
First
我要谢谢你 哈利
I want to thank you Harry
你在密室中 定对我表示出绝对的忠诚
You must have shown me real loyalty down in the Chamber
否则福克斯也不会被召唤到你身边
Nothing but that could have called Fawkes to you
至于
And
第二
second
我觉得
I sense that
你好像被什么事困扰着
something is troubling you
对不对 哈利
Am I right Harry
这
It's just
是这样的
you see sir
我注意到我跟汤姆瑞斗之间似乎在某些方面
I couldn't help but notice certain things certain
拥有相似的特质
Certain similarities between Tom Riddle and me
我知道
I see
没错
Well
你会说爬说语 哈利 为什么呢
you can speak Parseltongue Harry Why
这是因为
Because
佛地魔
Lord Voldemort
也能说爬说语
can speak Parseltongue
如果我没弄错的话 哈利
If I'm not mistaken Harry
他把一些力量转移到了你身上
he transferred some of his powers to you
就在他给你头上留下疤痕的那个晚上
the night he gave you that scar
佛地魔把一些力量转移到了我身上
Voldemort transferred some of his powers to me
这并不是他的原意
Not intentionally
但却是真的
but yes
所以分类帽说得没错
So the Sorting Hat was right
我应该就读斯莱特林
I should be in Slytherin
没有错 哈利
It's true Harry
你的确拥有一些佛地魔自豪的特质
You possess many of the qualities that Voldemort himself prizes
坚毅果敢
Determination
足智多谋
resourcefulness
还有也不太遵守既定的规则
and if I may say so a certain disregard for the rules
可是为什么
Why then
分类帽会把你分到格兰芬多
did the Sorting Hat place you in Gryffindor
那是因为我的要求
Because I asked it to
这就对了 哈利 这就对了
Exactly Harry Exactly
这就是你跟佛地魔不同的地方
Which makes you different from Voldemort
让我们成为哪种人的并不是我们的能力
It is not our abilities that show what we truly are
而是我们的选择
It is our choices
如果你想验证
If you want proof
你为什么属于格兰芬多
why you belong in Gryffindor
那么我建议你
then I suggest you
仔细的看一看这把剑
look more closely at this
小心
Be careful
高锥客格兰芬多
Godric Gryffindor
只有格兰芬多的真正传人
It would take a true Gryffindor
才能拔出这把剑
to pull that out of the hat
多比
Dobby
原来他就是你的主人
So this is your master
你服侍的家庭就是马尔福家
The family you serve is the Malfoys
我待会见再跟你算帐
I'll deal with you later
不要挡路 波特
Out of my way Potter
那么是真的了
So it's true
你又回来了
You have returned
当学校的理事们知道
When the governors learned
金妮韦斯莱被抓到密室去以后
that Arthur Weasley's daughter was taken into the Chamber
他们认为
they saw
该把我找回来了
fit to summon me back
荒谬
Ridiculous
很奇怪是吧
Curiously
卢修斯
Lucius
有些理事说
several of them
如果他们不同意让我停职的话
were under the impression that you would curse their family
你就威胁说要诅咒他们全家
if they did not agree to suspend me in the first place
你怎么敢
How dare you
你说什么
Beg your pardon
对我来说唯一以及永远不变的牵挂
My sole concern has always been and will always be
就是这间学校的利益
the welfare of this school
当然还有
and of course
学生的安危
its students
我想凶手已经逮到了吧
The culprit has been identified
是吗
I presume
是啊
Yes
那么
And
是谁呢
Who was it
佛地魔
Voldemort
不过这一次
Only this time
他不只是利用别人来进行这些行动
he chose to act through somebody else
还透过这本日记
by means of this
我 我懂了
I I see
很幸运的
Fortunately
哈利波特发现了这件事
our young Mr Potter discovered it
我希望往后不会再有人把佛地魔的旧东西
One hopes that no more of Lord Voldemort's old school things
交到无辜的人的手中
should find their way into innocent hands
进行这些事的人将必须承担严重的后果
The consequences for the one responsible would be severe
那么
Well
让我们期待
let us hope
波特同学能永远在这里拯救所有的人
that Mr Potter will always be around to save the day
别担心
Don't worry
我一定会
I will be
邓不利多
Dumbledore
走吧 多比
Come Dobby
我们该走了
We're leaving
校长
Sir
这本日记可以给我吗
I wonder if I could have that
马尔福先生
Mr Malfoy
我有东西要还给你
I have something of yours
还我
Mine
我不知道你说些什么
I don't know what you're talking about
我想你很清楚
I think you do sir
那天在斜角巷就是你偷偷把这本日记放进了金妮的篮子里面
I think you slipped the diary into Ginny Weasley's cauldron that day at Diagon Alley
是吗
you do do you
那你怎么不想办法证明
Why don't you prove it
走吧 多比
Come Dobby
打开它
Open it
多比
Dobby
主人给了多比一只袜子
Master has given Dobby a sock
什么 我没有
What I didn't give
主人给了多比衣物
Master has presented Dobby with clothes
多比现在自由了
Dobby is free
你害我失去了我的仆人
You lost me my servant
你不可以伤害哈利波特
You shall not harm Harry Potter
你的父母就跟你一样好管闲事
Your parents were meddlesome fools too
记住我的话 波特
Mark my words Potter
很快的
One day soon
你的下场就会跟他们一样的悲惨
you are going to meet the same sticky end
哈利波特让多比得到了自由
Harry Potter freed Dobby
多比要怎么报答你呢
How can Dobby ever repay him
答应我一件事就好
Just promise me something
我什么都答应
Anything sir
千万不要再想办法来救我了
Never try to save my life again
欢迎回来 尼克爵士
Welcome back Sir Nicholas
谢谢你
Thank you
晚安 尼克爵士
Good evening Sir Nicholas
晚安
Good evening
真高兴能见到你 尼克爵士
Good to see you Sir Nicholas
谢谢
Thank you
你好
Hello
赫敏
Hermione
欢迎回来
Welcome back
谢谢你 尼克爵士
Thanks Sir Nicholas
哈利
Harry
赫敏回来了
It's Hermione
欢迎你回来 赫敏
Welcome back Hermione
能回来真好
It's good to be back
恭喜你们 你们竟然解开了
Congratulations I can't believe you solved it
那都是因为有你
We had loads of help from you
没有你 我们什么都解不开
We couldn't have done it without you
谢谢
Thanks
各位同学请注意
Could I have your attention please
在宴会开始之前
Before we begin the feast
让我们先掌声感谢
Let us have a round of applause
苗芽教授
for Professor Sprout
庞芮夫人
Madam Pomfrey
谢谢他们以曼德拉草药
whose Mandrake juice
成功救回了所有遭到石化的人
has been so successfully administered to all who had been Petrified
另外 基于最近发生的事件为了表示心意
Also in light of the recent events as
学校决定所有的考试 都取消
a school treat all exams have been canceled
哦 不会吧
Oh no
抱歉 我来晚了
Sorry I'm late
那只带来释放我文件的猫头鹰迷路了
那是因为The owl that delivered my release papers got all lost and confused
一只叫爱洛的笨鸟
Some ruddy bird called Errol
我必须告诉你这件事
And I'd just like to say
如果没有你们的话 哈利 罗恩
that if it hadn't been for you Harry and Ron
当然还有你赫敏
and Hermione of course
我现在还得待在那个地方
I would still be you know where
我要跟你们说的是谢谢
so I'd just like to say thanks
霍格沃茨不能没有你 海格
There's no Hogwarts without you Hagrid